{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "What is the highest mountain range in the world?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Himalayas",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Himalayas are the highest mountain range on Earth, located in Asia and spanning several countries."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known as the 'Roof of Africa'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Kilimanjaro",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Kilimanjaro, located in Tanzania, is the highest peak in Africa and is often referred to as the 'Roof of Africa'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range separates Europe from Asia?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Ural",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Ural Mountains form a natural boundary between Europe and Asia, running through Russia and Kazakhstan."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is home to Mount Everest?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Himalayas",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Mount Everest, the highest peak in the world, is located in the Himalayas in Asia."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range runs along the western coast of South America?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes is the longest mountain range in the world, stretching along the western coast of South America."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its stunning fjords?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Alps",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Alps, located in Europe, are famous for their picturesque fjords and breathtaking landscapes."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is nicknamed the 'Backbone of North America'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Rockies",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Rockies, stretching from Canada to the United States, are often referred to as the 'Backbone of North America'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is home to the Matterhorn?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Alps",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Matterhorn, one of the most iconic peaks in the world, is located in the Alps."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its active volcanoes?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes is home to numerous active volcanoes, making it a geologically active mountain range."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is located in the western United States?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Rockies",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Rockies are situated in the western part of the United States, spanning several states."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its ski resorts?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Alps",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Alps are renowned for their world-class ski resorts, attracting winter sports enthusiasts from around the globe."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is home to the Appalachian Trail?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Appalachians",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Appalachian Trail, a famous hiking trail in the United States, runs through the Appalachian Mountains."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its diverse wildlife, including llamas and condors?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes is home to a wide range of unique wildlife, such as llamas and condors."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is located in the southern part of South America?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes extend through the southern part of South America, crossing multiple countries."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its stunning lakes, including Lake Louise?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Rockies",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Rockies boast breathtaking lakes, such as Lake Louise, known for their crystal-clear waters."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is located in the eastern part of the United States?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Appalachians",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Appalachians stretch along the eastern part of the United States, from Alabama to Maine."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its ancient ruins, including Machu Picchu?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes house remarkable ancient ruins, such as the famous Incan city of Machu Picchu."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is located in the central part of Europe?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Alps",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Alps are situated in the central part of Europe, spanning multiple countries including Switzerland and Austria."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is known for its rich biodiversity, including snow leopards and red pandas?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Himalayas",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Andes",
            "Rockies",
            "Alps"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Himalayas are renowned for their incredible biodiversity, housing unique species like snow leopards and red pandas."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which mountain range is located in the western part of South America?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andes",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rockies",
            "Alps",
            "Himalayas"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Andes stretch along the western part of South America, running through countries like Peru and Chile."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}